Friends, in today's video we will discuss
some such important points that when you
talk to a customer on call,
they are very helpful for you during that time, in
which the first is communication skill.
Suppose you call a company to
buy an office chair, then
your call gets connected with the sales executive there,
now he is talking to you, now
you have to buy it, that is why you have called,
but suppose he is
not able to talk to you properly, is not able to explain to you,
you have many
doubts regarding the product, he is not able to clear it, then
what will happen is that you will talk to him, you will
listen to whatever he says,
but you will not buy his product. So,
you must keep this thing in mind that
whenever you talk to a customer on call, during
that time you should talk to the customer well,
like your
way of talking should be proper, your voice should be
clear and it should
not be that you are
explaining something very quickly and also it should not be that you are speaking
very slowly.  You are slowly
telling the customer about your product. Do
not fail to be naive and confidently discuss all the
product related matters
with the customer, only then will the customer
purchase your product. Next is
listening. Whenever you talk to a customer on call,
give importance to the customer, give him value.
Listen carefully to whatever he says and
understand it carefully and then reply to it. If
you do not listen to the customer properly, then
how will you be able to reply to him? The
customer should feel that you are
giving him your valuable time. It is
not that you are ignoring his call,
you are not giving importance to his words.
If the customer feels even a little bit that you are
not giving him value, then he will
talk to you, he will understand and listen to everything you say,
but later he will
not purchase the product from you because the customer
goes only to the place where he gets value
because it is not that the customer is
wasting your time, it is your product itself.  He
will buy it and later he will also make the payment,
so the company also makes a profit from
it, so you should listen to the customer carefully,
understand him and
explain the product to him well. Next is patience.
You know this thing that whenever an incoming call
comes, like a customer has a
requirement and he
wants to buy the product himself, then he calls the company, then
obviously he talks nicely
because he has a requirement and he is
not satisfied with it. But sometimes it happens that the
company people give us some letters to
convert that you have to
deal with so many customers, so there we
think that how will we deal with so many customers,
but when the call is connected,
those customers do not have the requirement
of the product, they should buy from the company,
but we have to convince them, so
as soon as we talk to the customer, many
times it happens that the customer gets very
frustrated and talks to you angrily, saying that
I have not made any inquiry,
why are you bothering me.  He calls
you and says such things to you, but
you have to be patient there, you should
not talk angrily there, even if the customer
shouts at you in anger, you should
not reply back to him
because if you talk to him angrily, what will happen is that
he will
disconnect the call and that customer will go away
from you, but you have to keep in mind
that you are working for that company,
you are there as an employee and your
job is to please the customer,
you should have some patience there and
talk to him in a positive way, it is okay if
he purchases your product or not,
but at least there is a chance
that the customer will listen to you carefully after some time,
and many times it happens that
we talk about the customer's need, like if
we talk about the thing he needs, then the
customer definitely stops for two minutes and
listens to what he says, and if not now, then
in the future he says that no,
I do not have any requirement right now, but
in the future I will think about buying this product.  I will definitely
think about it. Next is knowledge about
product and service. Suppose you want to get your
bike insured and
for insurance you call a company and
say that I want to get it insured. Please
explain it to me in detail. Will it be
valid? Will
I get any benefits from it? Please explain all these things to me properly. So
what happens there? For example,
if you call and the person on the other side is not able to explain
everything properly. What happens there is that as soon as you
call him and he is
not able to explain you properly about the policy,
about the terms and conditions.
What will happen then is that you will
not buy insurance from him. You were wanting to make a purchase
because that is why you called him.
But if you feel that he was
not able to satisfy you because you will
also make the payment to him, then no customer will make the payment like this.
He makes the payment only after all his doubts are
cleared. So
what will you do at that time? You will
definitely listen to what he says but you will
not purchase insurance from him. So
you must keep this in mind.  You have to keep in mind that regarding whichever
product you are talking to the customer on call,
you should have complete knowledge about that product and
also about the company
because if you do
not have proper knowledge about the product service, then how will you clear the
doubts of the customer related to the product
and there you will not be able to express your views
with confidence and you will not have confidence in yourself,
so it is very important to have knowledge, along with this
you also have to keep in mind that
you should not make the customer feel bored during the call
because whenever you call the customer, at that time it should
not happen that the
way the customer is talking to you and the
questions he is asking you, instead of answering them,
you are answering them in a slightly different way,
whatever the customer asks,
answer it in the same way and give it limited, it is
not that if the answer is of 2 minutes,
stretch it and you are talking to the customer for 5 minutes,
you are also wasting your time  It wastes the
customer's time as well, so the customer
feels like what did you ask and what is the answer, you are
taking such a long answer,
then he will not like to talk to you there, so at
that time you should focus on the call
and tell the customer only as much as
he asks and discuss with him all the important things about your company,
about the product, about the service, if
you feel that it is
not necessary to tell him then do
not explain the entire script to him, this
saves your time too friends, apart from this, to know
what other things should be kept in mind while talking to the customer on call,
you can watch this video, the link of which
is given in the i button or you
can visit our channel, so we will meet
in the next video with a new topic, thank you